Dan Achim

Email: dan@hostatic.ro
Phone: +40724507109
https://hostatic.ro
Bucharest, Romania

Summary

Experienced and passionate systems engineer focused on Linux, Open Source software, automation, configuration management and continuous integration. Professional experience ranges from designing, deploying and automating Linux and OSS based infrastructures to running high traffic web sites where uptime is vital. Former owner of a small ISP and hosting business.

Abilities include configuring and managing high-traffic web servers, load balancing and scaling networked services, automating infrastructures, writing system tools and bridging the gap between development and operations. Business-minded and a good communicator. Ever-curious spirit, I love learning new things.

Skills

Linux | Centos | Debian | Configuration Management | Puppet | Ansible | Scalability | Load Balancing | Apache | Nginx | uWsgi | F5 Big-IP | haproxy | Virtualisation | KVM | Docker | Mesos | Marathon | AWS | Zookeeper | Bash | Python | Flask | Django | Mysql | Redis | Memcached | ElasticSearch | Monitoring | Nagios | Graphite | Kibana | Grafana | git | Bind | PowerDNS | Postfix | Continous Integration and deployment

Strong analytical and troubleshooting skills | Ability to handle a fast-paced environment | Technical leadership | Managing a project from start to end | Autonomous and able to handle geographically distributed teams

Professional experience

Senior DevOps engineer @ creative.ai, Remote, Everywhere

May 2017 - Present

Designing and implementing the infrastructure on which the <u>creative.ai</u> platform will run:

- Created an easy to use development environment based on Docker containers
- Implemented a continuous integration system using Travis, NodeJS and Docker

- Deployed a staging and production environment using Docker Swarm on top of AWS' EC2 for backend hosting and CloudFront / S3 for frontend serving
- Automated everything using a mix of Ansible and Terraform

DevOps consultant @ iMedicare, Remote, Everywhere

October 2016 - May 2017

Helping iMedicare scale and improve their AWS infrastructure.

- Introduced monitoring tools like Graphite, Grafana and the Elasticsearch / Kibana / Logstash stack for better insight into their infrastructure
- Improved the load balancing and CDN setup with a mix of AWS ELB, S3 and Nginx
- Development environment based on Docker and Jenkins powered CI pipeline

Senior Linux Systems Engineer @ Booking.com, Bucharest, Romania

August 2013 - July 2016

- Have been directly involved in growing the <u>company's</u> infrastructure from around 1000 servers in one datacenter to over ten 10000 spread across 3 datacenters, all while scaling Puppet and its recipes to keep up with this growth
- Wrote tools to help manage the multi-DC setup and failover easily using Django, Zookeeper and Redis
- Introduced Docker, Mesos and Marathon in a single, easy to use and smooth to adopt platform
- Helped my team move to a new paradigm in monitoring, based on Bosun, Grafana and Kibana
- Wrote a HTTP REST API to manage F5 load balancers using Python, Flask and Redis.
- Created an automated Wordpress deployment and hosting infrastructure backed by Puppet,
 Nginx and Php-fpm
- Handled capacity testing and improved server deploy automation by tweaking the Puppet recipes

Linux Systems Engineer @ Booking.com, Amsterdam, Netherlands

April 2010 - August 2013

- Deployed, maintained and automated hundreds of Nginx based web servers and F5 load balancers.
- Managed the <u>Puppet infrastructure and refactored internal core modules</u>. Taught at Puppet intro classes for new employees.
- Deployed a top-notch, KVM based, development environment that reduced the setup time for a newly hired developer from one day to two hours.
- Helped grow the team from 10 to 22 members by on-boarding newly hired engineers
- Improved capacity, reliability, monitoring and documentation of the Memcached infrastructure.

Linux Systems Administrator @ Gameloft, Bucharest, Romania

December 2008 - April 2010

Part of the Global Network Services team inside Gameloft, maintaining Gameloft's Linux Debian

based infrastructure and the game web shop. This included:

Apache web-servers that ran behind relayd load-balancers

• Mysql clusters.

• Postfix mail-servers and the xmpp messaging servers.

• Puppet code base.

Linux Systems & Network Engineer @ Spanning, Bucharest, Romania

October 2006 - November 2008

Engineering and maintaining everything from Linux servers to Cisco routers and firewalls. Network

design, infrastructure services (mail, web, file-sharing, databases), VPNs, network security.

Self-employed / Owner @ small local ISP, Bucharest, Romania

August 2006 - June 2008

I was the founder of a small local ISP. I was also for a large part of its life, the only technical

employee. I designed and configured the access network from zero, taking care of everything

throughout the OSI Layers: from cables to switches and routers. The stack was exclusively Linux

and Open-source.

Volunteer experience

Developer and systems administrator @ Funky Citizens, Bucharest, Romania

October 2014 - Present

Helping Funky Citizens - a NGO - and the constellation of organisations and projects around it

host their online presence and develop new web applications.

Education

• Spiru Haret University, Bucharest, Romania

• George Cosbuc High School, Bucharest, Romania

Languages

· Romanian: native

English: fluent